in an equilateral triangle with area one
first start by tricing the three sides
of the triangle then bict the three
sides of the triangle as well connect
vertices to opposite Tri sectors like
this and connect the remaining Tri
sectors to the midpoints each of these
six shaded regions makes up exactly 17th
of the triangle as you can see by
rotating here therefore we've shaded 67
of the triangle the center triangle is
therefore 17th of the area of the
original we can repeat this process on
the inner 17th shading 67 of 17th so
shading 6 of 7^ squar repeat this
process over and over again each time
shading 67 of the remaining 1 over 7 to
the N if we consider the infinite sum
which corresponds to the limiting
process eventually the entire triangle
will be shaded and that means that the
infinite sum we have is equal to 1 one
interpretation is that 6 repeating in
base 7 is equal to 1 another one is that
6 * the infinite sum of the powers of
17th is 1 so that the infinite sum of
the powers of 17th is 1 16